Okay, so the last exercise I'm going to show you is for the lower back.
Really important place to work and a lot of people forget to do it or just don't feel like doing it because it's not one of those things that they're always looking at in the mirror, but it's so important.
Especially as you get older and you kind of start to hunch over, if your abdominals and lower back are not strong.
So, I'm going to show you some exercises that you may already know, but in progression.
So, this is just called a quadruped.
Making sure that your body is nice and straight and that your shoulders, watch out for the tent shoulders dropping.
So all you're going to do is extend that right arm and if you're able to extend the left leg or just the opposite leg and arm and just hold it for about 5 to 10 seconds and then slowly come down and switch.
The big mistake I see people make here is they kind of wiggle around and they kind of lift too high and then they drop it down.
Everything needs to be done very slowly and deliberately.
Lift and lower.
I would do 10 times on each side and then you're going to make it a little bit tougher, you're going lift, hold and then try without moving your body, pull the elbow into the knee without moving the rest of your body, you can move the elbow and knee and then bring it right back out again and then switch.
This just adds a little dimension to it.
Pulling in, makes it just a tiny bit tougher, out, and drop and again.
I try to get my clients to do about 5 to 10 reps on each side, hold it 5-10 seconds and down.
I always end them with cat stretches.
Which I'm sure you've seen, but you want to make sure you do right.
So you're just going to drop and then just like a cat when it gets scared, you just round out your back.
I see a lot of people who kind of do stuff with their upper body, that's not how it is, you want to keep your shoulders nice and low, straighten out, round out, exhale, get it all out and then drop and flatten it out again like you're a table and then pull in.
Exhale as you pull in and drop.
That should be a really relaxing exercise and really relaxing way to kind of finish off your workout.
Make sure that you keep that breathing going and just let it go and then just give yourself a hand for doing such a good job.
We've did a whole bunch of exercises that don't require anything but your body and you can do them anywhere.
I hope that you had a good time and remember you want to keep good form, keep the abdominals working at all time and you can always email me at heatherrider.com, if you have any questions.
Nothing should hurt, your knees shouldn't hurt, your back shouldn't hurt, you should just feel good and worked out after this workout.
Hope you had fun.